and then yes the delivery here are working are working really for the technical part because
both of our liberty are are struggling sometimes on situation of the line on ball strong
but really it's more like technical part you know what i ask what i ask we have a good attitude in
situation of the defense this to everybody but in this moment delivery is that i don't ask to have
the platform extended of the arm so not the arm far from the body like they can have in situation
of reception when they push the ball but really what i ask is to have the legs leg and the elbow
near near to the body elbow mirror and and the palm of the palm of the the hands up because
one ball arrived really really quick i don't forbid to the player to
to have also
one reaction into defense one for example one slide quick when they are sharp and maybe they
are moving from from perimeter because maybe there was you know it was take care about one tip or
there wasn't one situation of transition that they set but to react quickly even with uh with open
with open up with operands sorry
and here we continue exclamatory then second coach attack situation of super libero set
and then the other libero defense on the parallel the and the sector and the setters
in this moment the sector are all the time in second line and i think if i
remember good after the setter moved uh moving first line here i was
yes i was explained to the player you know because they was it was like uh throwing you know they was
throwing the the convents and is not to throw just really to to do the movement need to spend more time in team defense dynamic tilester use that defenders powered to the elephant here i was like throwing you know they was throwing the the cones and his though to throw just reading both movement just to do the movement and east.
to keep the movement of the defense and the corners have to go out alone.
You know, they don't have to throw the ball, the cones, they are like this and
they go and they go quick with the platformer, to put together the platform
and to react to the really quick ball.
Movement.
Exactly.
This is, she did really good.