in general like you have a new player you know you have a new player coming to you
how how does it start and how do you go through the season like what is there you know what i
mean like how do you go about having a new player and explain like okay this is what we do this is
what i believe in this is how i see you in my team and then how do you evaluate during the season
yes yes yes that is normally i'm honest all the time and that that we sang one player i like
from the beginning to speak with them before to before to start before to sign i like to know
who will be one my player so i like to speak with them in the beginning but after when we start the
season generally i after three week after three four week there are no way it's three weeks we
did this year depending for it a bit about the verification it's dependable the player that
they are for example initial team i use it to do the individual meeting
so
just some individual meeting normally i work like that i let i let the player at home one paper i
print one paper with normally it's nine questions so i like to give a nine question to the player
and of course there is playing really good to them that there is confidence and it's it's a question
and that's what that i totally read just me there is no stuff inside it's just my my part okay that
is kind of some of of question and after that i plan in the in the schedule normally it's around
30 minutes of meeting that i do one by one with them and we you know we read we read what they
what they write what they write really honestly really open there is some question more more
technically so it's like what you would like to improve what you feel that it's your weak part of
what you feel that is like a strong part what you would like to improve what you think about
for example about tactical work about tactical park part what you think what you how you consider
the physical part and then in the in the last question there is more more little bit the you
know the more like a personal situation because i like also for example the last question that
they put that i like so much it what is your professional dream i i like so much to post this
kind of question and uh it's really really nice sometimes funny also to see the answer
i you know you can have one player that that say
my dream is to go to play in italy my dream
is you know you can have one player that that say you can have a player that that say
is to go to play in turkish my play my dream is to win olympic game but it's also so different
because this year one my player right my dream is to don't have any more pain on the knee
and this let me let me really think a lot because you know i was one my first year in one new
project here in paris so i thought a lot about how was example before the medical situation the
physical situation that we changed so much i introduced one therapist full time that before
was not there and i can say that for example now that it's march this player don't have any more
pain in the knee and she she realized one dream it's for me it's really important to work with
with the player like that because because you can understand also a lot of feedback from your
for your player and i believe so much that that you need to work with the video
player and to have one really really honest and open open communication with them if you
want get something with them you need to be open i think credible to have to have a real honest and
clear and clear feedback and communication with them another question that they do in the beginning
of of the the nine it's how you feel in paris no was this year last year was how you feel in
accent province but
i say how you feel here you feel good how you feel now because uh arrived to me when this year arrived
to me and one player say that for her was really difficult because of apartment because was some
trouble you know this make you make me make me thought and this can give me the the feedback to
to work for example with the club to say there's always a situation about this player because it's
important for me that one player still good in uh in in the situation then okay
in french it's probably a little bit different about for example italy even if i'm italian
because there is a lot the the position also the head coach a little bit like a manager you know so
i i work so much even with this kind of situation in the club to to try to to manage also some other
situation that go not completely on the sport part but also to manage these other situation
but i like so much to to have this
uh this feedback uh this bit with the player another question for example it's how you feel
with your like i say it's after three maybe week how you feel with your with your teammate
and now you in the locker room and how you feel with the staff
is generally the the nine question that they do that they do with the player and this give me give
me so much i i go i read before i read at home everything and then i do individual meeting with
them
and this is i think is really the beginning of all the relationships that we that we fix
yes yes yes exactly and then that's what is the so this is the start of the season like
you do something similar again at the end or before the playoffs or at new year or i do
i do normally three times one individual meeting like fix with the player three times in a season
to give feedback so if something that is not acceptable for you you do it again and it's
a good way to get back to playing in the game with the team then you know the team develop
your team i think it's also important to be consistent with your current set of
Oregon and then also to watch your starting team or your starting
more to do to one player what we need to work better and more about maybe one week part but
even something like more to fix the good part you know what for me this is really important for
example to don't fix too much the objective just on the weak part of one player but also to work
on the strong part and because especially with with women in my opinion is not to use too much
the word you know bad don't like this no for me it's you can do like this it's not too much to
say to to focus too much on the mistake but to to show and to give to them the way how to resolve
one problem for example so this is something that i do in the half of the season and then generally
yes in the in the end of the season there is all the time one one one feedback
one feedback
one one meeting that i do with the player to understand how was going the season and
even more in one project you know when we continue together with the with the player how can be the
transition part and how can be the second season in one project to build something you know it's
important for me when you work with with one player maybe for one more season with two or three
seasons and it's what it's happening what happened to me in the last two seasons even hell but what
what is happening also now in paris no that i continued with one player and this is really
important because for example i have player that that stay that decide also to continue the project
because they wanted to improve more and and so this is a real honest feedback that i give to
the player and and they give really honestly i don't have nothing to to say about it but i think
it's important for me to be able to sell you know i have here displayed to one player that maybe there
is still a range to improve or not because i cannot sell to one player there is to improve
if i don't believe if i don't believe to improve there is not anymore the right environment and
the right the right the right work but this is a little bit how i'm working