Normally, the first couple of minutes of reception, I like so much to use one ball, if you see.
I saw it. I was watching it when I was reading it. I was like, why are they doing this? So I'm very curious.
I work all the time in the beginning, but really the first minute, two minutes, because it's really easier with this inverted spin to push the ball.
And in my opinion, in the beginning, it gives a lot of confidence also to the receiver.
So in the beginning, just a couple of minutes to feel better the ball with this inverted spin, that it's much, much more easier to push.
Try one day in a TS if you want, if you remember something.
It's still possible.
Yes, but it's really easier.
It's really easier and gives a lot of confidence.
It gives a lot of confidence to the receiver to push the ball.
This is just warm up.
It's just warm up of reception with inverted spin.
After we go, we go with normal situation of flop.
Here the receiver, like you can see, they are working more line to line.
Libero on the other side, of course, don't work in five, but work with our system that step on the left and take the ball.
They go to cover outside hitter of reception, first line.
So go step on the left and then we change.
There is a lot of ball that stay after reception from five line to line that stay in position three and not too much in position two three.
At this I ask how much that really the platform, the platform from service line to line in five, the real platform and the shoulder give orientation really to position two three.
And to don't let the ball in the middle of the net.
This is one important objective that I ask to the receiver of five.