This is a, this is one exercise that I do.
And I, and I re I call a shoulder blade is exercise.
I really, I really do to feel the shoulder blade of reception.
This one.
Okay.
I remember now.
Yes.
This is still with the, with easy ball because, uh, it's what I
said before a little bit, no, they have to feel that they have to feel
it is a scapulata we say in Italian, the shoulder blade that go to finish
the movement and the platform finish the movement, even with the shoulder blade.
I believe so much in the situation of reception about also the
mobility of the shoulder blade.
And so what, what they, what they do here, they're trying to put one
reception precise in position to work for, you know, this is one really,
really good way.
That they can feel the couple, you know, the shoulder blade that push in the other
side, I continue to use this like warmup, but also like technical, but this is a
little bit about, you know, also the, what, what you need in there, what you
search, what is in this moment also the, the, uh, the week maybe part of the
reception and in this moment, we was, in my opinion, I remember this morning, I
see the match, the last match.
We was working a little bit less with this, uh, with this, uh, lateral
situation of, uh, the reception and with the teaser orientation.
And for example, we was one mistake, you know, it's all the time to touch
the ball and to open the arm, you know, to go, to go, to don't keep the
platform during exercise, platform, PDL, if one of second, the platform in
reception and, and to open the, to open the arm.
Yeah.
And here in this exercise, they really can feel that the ball, the pushing, they
keep one second, the platform, if you can see quite, quite good, everybody, they
keep, and then they relax.
Okay.
We work, uh, service one, one to five with like pushing the ball in position two.
And after we change, we change.