so no now what we have here is two groups it's middles and opposites
so we are doing an exercise that is a defense from the coach then the middle blocker on the
other side have to read the they have to read the the set of whoever is setting in this case
can be either setting the the middle blocker or the opposite and then we are working on
on trying to have a big first step in block trying to read the ball and trying to read
the ball and then just turning we don't jump in the morning it's very unusual that we jump
in the morning i don't like it i i just don't like it so and then after the if we are just
focusing on this focus on trying to focus on the first step that was something that we do a lot
a lot like a negative step like the first step goes behind your line so we are focusing a lot to
to try to to have this big step to to reach a lot of core and get faster to the ping no and then we
we add one set so you turn we pretend that there is a defense on the other side and a middle blocker
after the the blocking movement she turns and said and at the same time we try to with it we we have
tried to pretend both coaches on the pins are like real hitters so then after we also do a defense
from a real attack right from a real set so and that sometimes it's different to play defense
with a set with somebody said it that with a with a coach tossing the wrong ball you know so
this is basically what we are doing now here like focusing a little bit on
just the block without blocking and just the movements and some setting and business
no yet here for example we have now we have the centers delivered or not to the to the squad and
that's the
only jump that i do in the morning the the set for sure you have to read sometimes in the morning
and i'm tossing on one side and then the other set that it's passing like setting real reception
from one then we have um we have uh the middles in the and the opposites sent into our liver
and then after playing defense because the drill before was a little bit more controlled it was
not real defense because that's one of the things that i always say when we are doing
these kind of drills with the coaches like because sometimes you have to do a little bit more control
and sometimes we push too much the drill in the morning was setting it's not defense so like in
the morning i mean earlier in the morning the first drill it's setting not it's not defense so
you need a certain control there to to be able to set in good condition right so now now now they
are serving and then doing the normal approach for uh for defense and and then they get a
they get a ball from um from the coach uh so on one side that they they said that they're going to
reset and coming from one and me i'm creating a little bit some footworks you know like
sometimes in systems sometimes out of system like we are changing a little bit what kind of uh
what kind of uh footwork we want to want we want to work on and uh this is important because lately
i a lot of teams uh you know they they serve tactically to one a lot so i think
centers have to feel comfortable with the ball coming from one especially especially okay okay
uh some you you find some tips including me that sometimes uh uh you just said to one because it's
just more uncomfortable to set your middle if the ball is a little bit of the net or you become a
little bit more readable uh you know with the ball coming from one so that's why i i really
put another volume on on on on our setters work with the within general coming everything from
one like transition six one or or reception for one one setter is setting four with the reception
from one the other set is setting back with the reception for one so we are working at both uh
both directions now let's just say i mean you only defend from the aim yeah i only change the
direction spike from the other side yeah yes the setters they can choose the tempo that they that
they set or it's more right yeah yeah they can choose i mean normally before yeah the same they
can they can not all our players have the same tempo right we had some players that they need a
ball and yeah it's it's hard some i work a lot with the with the tempo hoop not only with the
location group but it's with the bowling system right it's just an analytic job with the with
the setters i choose the high where between this this between the hoop and the and the center
and then we say okay this is the high you have to set and and kind of it's a it's the ball the ball
that the the ball the speed that i wanted for but once you have more people and
because i use another hoop between the between the location hoop and the center i use a tempo hoop so
you cannot you cannot when you are doing uh like another kind of job with defense middles and like
this yeah so yeah you have to play to the first hoop to get the right curve to get to the second
not through not not through i i play all day some people remove the
the net in the middle of the hoop and then they try to play through what i do is
i i choose i mean i put the hook up and then i choose normally i'm like
in the one two three normally i try to put the hoop in the fourth in the fourth white
so let's say like one or two um lines from the below the antenna no the top of the antenna yeah
yeah so 2010 is lower than around 20 yes yes there is one morning practice just for the centers and
video and you do that um uh yeah okay okay after we finish this i will i will find it for once again
but this is the this this uh i i think it's always fair especially because he was to me one of the
greatest guy that i met in my life for sure you you you knew him but uh that the temple hoop uh
told me miguel angel falasca he told me he told me ah do you work only with loki because
we did the coaching the coaching license we did it together and then also we knew each other for a
long time and and his brother villermo and every time after the after the classes we were going to
have a beer and and then i kind of learned more from him that's from from anyone else as he and
he wasn't he was getting the license right and he told me look uh the best way like i was asking
advices and everything and i admired him i grew up playing and he was like start and so he told me
about this the tempo hoop and and since then after that that summer i started working since 2014 i
worked with the with the tempo hoop so just that the setters get used to and get used to the high
of the ball so now the middle blockers were the whole time seven to one right uh so now we do a
little bit of service to five i just
see everybody middles and opposites are 75 and then the libero is doing a little bit of
defense with centers you know just to finish the probably just to finish the the whole training
yeah that's exactly yeah we arrived at 37. everybody was serving to one so
so yeah to have a little bit of volume on scene three and four i i put two two targets but you
cannot see from here because i don't know if you see it's like small uh combs uh
yellow
and i have four or the four seams seen once in two since recent four and then so when they are yeah
yeah i know yeah you see you see it but you see it really bad as you convert the look yeah yeah
exactly so trying to find the scene between both outsides and yeah and the sidelines yeah now
the outside hitters come and and yeah the the the setters give the
set out of reception always from one right either from the liver or or me doesn't
and now i bring the the outside hitters and then i like always
i put a lot of volume in in this connection especially in the scene i try to work a lot on it
and always with both outsides for sure the outsides are going to play together or they play
together more often right but you will see you see that everybody i try to change and to make all the
all the
uh jejkijone.
couples yes passing and then for sure
also all the all the outsides go with it with the libero for the same for the same reason and
then you have one set that's setting back and the other side setting fired then the wheel rotates
and yeah also that if we take the next video after this um there is the player that's injured
and she's doing the receiving from a chair is there also some like more technical work then
you do this oh no no no no no oh there isn't even anOD上
i normally don't spend so much time in in this kind of analytic
job i always prefer to to have a as real as you can i understand that we go to this debate of
what kind of philosophy you like a little bit more like you know there are always these two tendencies
is like everybody say that i have another tendency that these two tendencies not the
brazilian or the america oh like a little bit more analytic with the coaches uh
from the box and and doing a lot of repetition that is the brazilian and and then the american
that it's more like trying to read the game the coaches are not so involved in the in the practice
and so i try a little bit at both so at the end the coaches are serving uh
but i mean we are serving uh we try to always you need for example there i'm trying to find the left
to work with the left i'm trying then probably the next go to the scene okay again to the left
but i'm trying to you know we are trying to create situations with the real set you know
working to the scene there so i i prefer that the coach of the box and and try to serve trying to
create a situation okay let's focus a little bit on the right and let's focus a little bit on the
left then
uh this technical job because slow to open up and but no no normally we don't spend so much time in
this kind of uh let's say youth work or yeah so it's more about having the couple perform a
reception connect together sometimes sometimes okay ricky ricky's serving for five i'm serving
for one sometimes we we try to we try to move the box a little bit especially when
the service from one like bring it a little bit more inside because then the the priority
the scene is not taken by six it's taken by five so then to try to create different stimulus to try
to create different different discussions now the um in the outside say this is my board this
is your board if it drops it's mine if it goes long it's yours you know i always like for example
with that here i i i try to tell always my outside that even if the ball goes to five
that the six should cross behind and take the long seat in case you know at last moment the
the outside uh decide to leave the ball for some reason and then we have the we have the the six
try to take this long scene yeah i will i will try to find this one back because we just had
your six doing this like cutting behind and i think yeah come now yeah we can wait 30 seconds
to see if it comes or not it was a really good example of what you just said it's not coming but
man i will find an example to put to put inside it it was before i think so i don't know yeah
yeah the last part of it right yes so now okay like everybody like the outsides passed six
fives and six five with the liberals but they didn't pass for one right so now we have one
coaching serving one to one and another coach serving five to one and then we without the
setups because the set is already set with the ball coming for one so uh yeah they are
just doing as anyone the centers go to weights and now you see madison and yeah and you finish
the practice the the thing is like i do three three i not don't always do the same the same
practice i'm trying to change sometimes different things so for example normally i do defense but
we we do three morning uh three morning groups during the during a normal week right when we
play just one game on saturday sometimes we do defense sometimes we do defense and reception
yeah only a little bit of serving defense it depends change a little bit no good let me skip
until the end but i think this is i think they just they changed yeah okay this is the end
yeah stop share i will try to find the one with the with the temple it's a great name by the way
temple yeah it's for the temple because i believe it's good logic you can find it we can put it
wherever you want i mean if you put it high all the way but it's two antennas yes i don't know
i've seen all the coaches doing it after okay they were my players so and now they are coached
it was useful for them also