We have usually three balls.
We're going to go three sequence of three balls.
First ball is going to go middle blocker, go.
Middle blocker, go is basically middle blocker and super.
Is that right?
And next ball is going to go middle blocker or zone two.
Third ball, anything for an example.
Okay.
Anything goes on the third ball.
Or we can prescribe it even more right there.
My path suggests that we worked on, on paths that it's towards zone two.
Okay.
Because, and then you either work on a long string situation.
Now I can say either middle, or I can go left side to zone four, or we can also
work on a short string situation with means in this case, middle blocker or zone
two quick situation with zone two.
Is that right?
So we're creating all these situations where our middle blockers need to need to
react, but if we throw everything at them, it's impossible.
So that's, again, we go through progression through a year,
through two, three semesters.
We start right now, only eight ball to the left side.
And maybe two weeks from now, it's going to be, Hey, let's throw in
middle blocker and left side.
Is that right?
Zone four.
So there's a lot of progression.
It's not, let's just go defend four routes at the same time.
And we give them, we give them feedback and how they stand.
And probably, I don't know what our focus was here.
Um, if you look at my practice plan, you have it.
In front of you.
What's our focus here in ball setter ball here, you're going to see
there's a focus for blockers BF.
Um, and, um, yeah, we worked through these progressions over and over and
again, so they feel comfortable when that happens in a game situation and same for.