press play yeah this is my favorite part of practice like we haven't even started practice
yet um like my uh my good friend jason watson who you had on your uh your pot your uh podcast
and interview or not website sorry um he's got a really good quote it's a it's what is how does
he say uh it's a shame to uh it's a shame to ruin this practice with practice you know like like
that a lot of times a lot of times the activities the kids are doing beforehand um and the way they
kind of self-organize into activities is some of my favorite stuff to watch so practice hasn't
started yet they just get into it like they uh you can see two girls are hugging each other there's
a lot of good vibes uh we got a couple of male practice players who are really excited to jump
in there um and they're just serve pass set competing back row they're just playing small
groups volleyball so um i often wonder like if i should just let this go
you
until they stop and then start practice um but i uh yeah i love this part you know coaches are
just checking in and um yeah this is my favorite part of practice and it's before practice even
starts so i'm not sure what that says about me as a coach but i enjoy this part no judgment man
so so at this point they did some warming up or they come out of the the weight room or
or they just come out of treatment they've done their little armbands um if anyone's
needs to throw balls against the wall or whatever they need to do they kind of do that and then
they've all like again practice hasn't started yet and now they're uh getting into deep court and
warming up and um you know i love it you have you have an opposite setting on the close side you
have a libero setting on the other side you have her setter it right back on the offensive side
like hoping the libero sets are i just love all the people playing different positions and
um yeah i just i just love this part
myself
skipping it a bit and then there's a couple of minutes of i guess explaining what this session
is about so we meet at the whiteboard i explain practice i'll try to give some kind of thought
for the day or you know those those are random how how i think of them or how i present them
and then we'll split up into three courts because we have three courts i know every gym is different
the number of assistants available is totally different for everybody um but the this is what
we call the warm-up so they've been messing around with the warm-up and they've been messing
around here they've they actually are warm because they've been playing um and i know uh like a lot
of club coaches at least in the states like they they have to stay within their practice times like
they can't show up early and start messing around so like again that's another luxury for us the
first activity we're doing when we split up on three courts is the warm-up so i'll go off to the
court on the left with the setters and some passers and i've got a couple guys who can uh
serve pretty hard jump floats at the passers
um so i'll be tutoring both i'll be tutoring the passers and the setters which i don't always
recommend as a coach because i you know you can only focus your attention on one thing at a time
um so usually uh for the first two three weeks of the season i just have setters over there and
i just have a coach tossing and maybe i'll even pass it so i can just focus on the setters
but as the season goes on it's it's it's too good of an opportunity not to get some live
passing reps and anytime passers can pass with uh setters and hitters on the court
it's going to be more transfer so so this time of the year i start going into uh passers and setters and i'll uh
kind of shift my feedback between the two of them um and then my other two assistants aaron johnson
and aaron benning will split up the other two courts based on you know what we talked about
earlier that day you know things we want kids to maybe they want more non-setter sets maybe
we want to get more digs maybe it's both maybe a couple kids need a specific uh focus so so they'll
break that up based on those things and that'll go about 15 minutes
we're also blocking and then yeah yeah i mean i think he's for having three middles and trying to
get a warm-up activity i think he's doing a pretty good job like they were just trying to get a few
specific situations on things that we've flubbed um these kind of drills are more i call these like
mental model drills like you know these are this is like a super blocked activity like we're not
going to get a ton of transfer out of it um but it uh it'll help uh it'll help them find it help
them from the matches prior and it'll just give us a nice reference point as we get into the rest
of practice but you can see he's doing it for a very short period of time um and uh drills like
this tend to work pretty well like after matches um you know if you're doing this before you've
been competing like this this is pretty useless um so like like i said so i think there's there's
engagement because of what happened in the weeks prior um we shouldn't be doing this very long it's
definitely a warm-up activity and probably part of it also is
uh our other assistant ej like who she had to take to work on some of the stuff she identified
for the warm-up i think kind of impacted this too but i think aaron's doing a good job with
what he has trying to make this as random as he possibly can more particularly just like you said
like these are three you know three or four exercises stacked straight up behind each other
for two minutes max every yeah yeah uh richard schmidt the motor learning pioneer who passed away
years ago um he had uh like his his guiding principle towards cognitive activities which
are just super blocked activities where um they should only be done to where the to where the
learner almost understands so like one of the mistakes with those is like you go you wait you
wait until the rep is perfect but the the drill itself is so controlled it doesn't matter if it's
perfect it's not gonna it's not gonna be anywhere close to that once you start leveling up so there
just needs to be enough of a recognition like okay i understand what we're talking about then
then you got to move on so you know that it tent
two minutes tends to be the upper threshold usually unless you have like 20 kids doing the
activity there might be like a little bit of an art to it too you know i mean like the the athlete
has to be doing pretty close to the motion that you want them to see to be successful um but we
don't need to like keep breaking it down and breaking it down until it's perfect because what
matters is once we start adding more noise to it you know so so it's you know that's where
that's where your coaching eye intuition has to come into like what what is close enough look
if they're doing X movement and you want Y movement you got to stay with it until there's
enough of an understanding but then it's that pocket of enough that's what we got to gauge as
teachers and then get out of it yeah yeah we're going to the next smaller exercise here with the
mills um 27 20. it's about to start right now okay this looks like a commit exercise or maybe
a digging exercise
let's see one more rep here yeah this looks like a uh a little bit of commit blocking work but more
of an emphasis on when the middle is digging for that half rotation when they serve um just
because obviously sometimes teams will try to pick on the middle when they're serving
um so we're just trying to give them a few more reps here uh again I think Aaron's doing a good
job he's making it as random as he can like the middle attacker is tipping and hitting so there's
a little bit of a read that's just a correctable opportunity right there it's just it's just a
teaching ball
um so yeah so again like the key uh I mean this is actually I think when it comes to digging I
think even if it's one-on-one it's it's a fairly noisy activity like especially if you're trying
to dig a quick hitter one-on-one um so I think there's a fair amount of transfer in this um not
maximum transfer because you're not getting the read like if they set the quick or the red but
when you're digging a quick hitter it's the it's the first thing that can happen
you know aside from the dump so it's pretty this drill might be a little bit more game-like than
even it appears because if the quick hitter hits the ball it's the first thing that can happen
anyway it's just like this drill so like we need to be able to attend to that but um so I think this
is uh it's pretty valuable activity but again that's I love the short period of time that
they're doing it so yeah after this it's again a short period of the whiteboards and yeah so at
this point we've explained practice
so they're just they're just going up to whiteboard because I have all these different
groups this group goes here this group goes here so they're just checking where their names are and
going to their corresponding courts we're not talking or anything at this point yeah so we're
doing uh so we're doing a doubles tournament so we've just broken up into three courts for the
warm-up and I like to do some kind of activity that uh Jim McLaughlin always said like get the
vibe right you know so I like to do some kind of like 15 minute it's usually like a high digging
activity um that gets people going uh so we like to play a doubles tournament
um we have on on the right side of the board we have everybody ranked one through 16 and we make
little brackets for doubles play um so what I do here I do something called the play of the day so
I just introduce a different play that people do in doubles and they can do it if they want and just
just trying to get their creativity gone but I think here I'm talking about uh a lot of the
creativity and doubles comes from the ability of the setter like can the setter back set can they
shoot set can they option can they fake option you know so I think here I'm talking about uh
talking about back setting yeah that's right so I'm talking about the ability to back set and
then your partner being able to swing one way or the other um so I love doing this because I I feel
like it indoor players are so structured I feel like it opens their minds a little bit and uh I
like the fact that I'm not bonusing it like so I just want it to be completely fun like I want them
to like try to do it just out of pride like just out of fun you know um and uh and then also just
expand the ranges of volleyball players so most non-setters aren't good at back setting so there's
um I just call it the play of the day I demo it uh there's some nice positive peer pressure here
like one kid volunteered to demo there you can see she's just you know I love that she's not that
good at it but she like went out there to be the demo of the team you can't really see it but the
team's cheering her on yeah uh and then we go out we just play three games of doubles in our brackets
like combination to seven points but um what I've noticed is like when someone gets the play of the
day they make sure I see it um and they'll scream it out really loud which is like the best so um
so it's just a little uh
yeah it's just just a way to broaden their game broaden their uh perspective um and then double
itself is just the best activity you could do right so it's serve pass that hit you got to read more
court than you do indoors you got to touch the ball more than you get to touch it indoors unless
you're an outside hitter um so it's just the best activity ever and it's competitive and there's a
ranking and no one wants to be at the bottom so you know this takes this uh I'm going pretty
long on this demo because it's the first time I've done this play of the day thing so yeah
playing days will be a little shorter but uh I think I'm actually talking too long here but but
the girls are probably into it that's why I'm doing it um and uh and then we'll go and play
in the play the once we start playing it takes about 10 minutes and team loves it and again it's
just the best I mean it's it's arguably top five volleyball activity you could do you know like if
you just play doubles and played sixes like it'd be impossible not to get better especially when
you like rank it and keep score and all that stuff so now they're going to go into their doubles
tournaments
um and they're just going to go off and play a combination of seven points so that the course
that they're in uh they're four people and they're all going to play each other so one two
versus three four one three versus two four uh one four versus two three um so it's just they're
just gonna play and then uh we got our assistant there at the white board and she's keeping track
of points and then we re-rank the board uh each day oh you saw a box a back set there right away
and she didn't overpass but she did in the the warm-up let's let's let this run for like 40 56
seconds just to see what happens sure again jump to the next one yes we got our libero passing and
hitting she's not bad there uh she actually has pretty good hand control like she can shoot pretty
well um so there's just all sorts of good stuff here it's just again it's just one of the best
activities you could do uh oh we have a little our middle went option yeah so we got our
opposite digging and you know uh sorry that's our Center actually that's our Center you know Carl
McGowan talked about uh developing generalized specialists so we want them to be uh specialized
at being volleyball players basically so you know that's that's where this activity comes
um so what I like about this I like what I really like about this practice so far is they showed up
early they were playing triples off of a serve before we even started um then we got into a warm
up activity and then now we're doing
triples so there's just all sorts of all you know everybody's touching the ball a lot everyone's
doing all the skills a lot uh they're competing um so just just all the things that you want to uh
develop volleyball players here you know middle setting although I was having to hit it over the
net um there's lots of rallies going on so it's just a lot of good stuff here let's go for one
more serve here and then you can go to the next one oh our setter is opting not to block she's
backpedaled okay so the middle is going to serve and run out which makes sense uh setter
got past the ball opposite back bumps at it chance to score here not a bad set by the middle yeah
there's a back set not good but that's okay she went for it so those are the kind of mistakes we
need to make and uh that's why I like not bonusing the play of the day just for doubles either again
I just want to be as fun as possible um and I and I think the the fact that a player was demoing
it during the play of the day I think that created and everybody was watching and cheering
her on I think that created a little healthy investment to be able to do that and that was a good surprise yeah I think that created a little healthy investments to turn it around and that was going to help us come back to our league.
make people want to actually do it once they got into that doubles tournament i think we've seen a
few back sets already um and then those mistakes that they make like the fact that the back sets
are really bad but they're still doing them anyways like those are exactly the kind of
mistakes you need to make to get better or something so um so i think as i'm watching
this part of my challenge is to extend these kind of situations to as many uh practice drills as
possible so this is now we're going into tutors so again i went with doubles to kind of get them
going and get a little higher paced activity now we're going into tutors so the far court that you
won't be you won't see will be a serving tutor so our assistant aaron benning who was working
with the middles there in the beginning uh he's all right he's focused almost entirely on serving
um as a coach and then uh the other two courts are going to be offensive tutors um so we'll see
how we break up i i think i do the outsides first in the first wave and then they switch
over to the serving court and do the middles but we'll see how i broke it up so i uh i think
right now i'm just explaining how we're going to break up but i i'm more if i'm talking this
long in tutors like they already know the deal it's because i want them to pay attention to the
focus of what they're going to be doing when they actually hit um so once they get out on the
i can explain a little bit more once i see it i'm gonna go there so 46 45
oh so the i see some outside i see some pin hitters going to serve so i'm probably gonna
do the middles first yeah so uh so we're working
on rotation two u.s rotation two we got a pass in the middle in the right so i think i'm trying
to get the server to jam the middle and the middle still to create a good entry uh based
on reading serve and reading the pass um so it's definitely this is a rotation two entry
uh and i'm standing back and i believe on the other court we're going from the other rotation
u.s rotation three uh so we're getting the quicks going from both sides and uh they're
going to rotate through on both courts
based on uh time and i'm standing i'm standing in a position where i can see both courts and
yell at them from both sides um so i i really uh i try to initiate off of a serve as much as i can
versus like a spin or a toss like we will still do that sometimes but i just want it to be as game
like as possible um because it's a good way to measure it like if you can't set the quick
off of a standing float um then you're not going to set it in a game so i think she she just
suggested to spin there i think
she's trying to give them both looks
and uh yeah so we're going uh so we're going from u.s rotation three on the right side that
you can't see and then u.s rotation two on this court uh and then setters and middles are going
to click back and forth um and uh at this point of the year i think i believe we're working on
our eye work so reading the serve reading the pass and then what kind of entry that we create
out of that to get the approach that we want um so this coach you see here casey she's focused
on services so she's talking a lot about the serve and the pass and then we're going to
move on to liberos and i love those plays so that's it's another reason i like to go off the
serve so obviously the more that you go off a serve the more random it's going to be i know
we when we run quick like we always want to create these drills where it's like perfect
pass perfect set but so much about it like is is the range that you can set the quick from
so if if you're always doing it off a serve you're just going to create all these different
opportunities to expand your range and i i love that um and i i love how it organically happens
so i've had i've had many seasons where we start firing quicks from off the net and i really
haven't talked about it it's just that the way that we introduce the drills the way that we do it
is random enough that they just and that that's that's the best because um if they're organically
doing it that means they're not really thinking about it which means it's going to transfer to
the game quicker because there's not all this like conscious thought about it so um those kind
of little opportunities are gold and um so yeah i really only try to go off like an easy i'll do
it easy when we're training middles i'll do an easy initiation only if it's a the beginning of
training we're trying to get some stuff in place um or if we're just sometimes i'll do it like hey
if we don't get an opportunity set the quick then throw in a toss so if we miss our serve or they
shank the pass then maybe we'll throw in a toss but we just but we keep serving so um yeah i just
i just love the randomness of it yeah so that time it worked out perfect which is fine yeah
it's gonna sometimes it's gonna be perfect yeah it's always lucky too i mean that's you know we
we have the coaches that we have like so i'm just fortunate that she's got a really good arm
she can float and spin and do also so you can see she's all
alternating her serves the types of serves so uh we're just really fortunate she has the arm that
she has we only have so much control over that with our coaching staff but she's doing a great
job of really making it random so just to be clear for the people watching you also have the
the monitors at the side of the courts right yeah so we have a layover yeah tell me yeah so
we have an ipad uh behind her we have it in the seam um so we can get the entire approach uh so
um you can see i got i have one of our male helpers doing a commit block um so this is
something i probably just introduced at this point so i think before this early in the year i wouldn't
have a commit blocker because we're just trying to get some basic movements in place but you know
now i feel like we have enough um clarity around it that i can start adding a block
so we have the ipad below behind her on a five second delay and then we have a tv next to her
it's connected to the ipad and she can just check and watch it anytime that they watch
i think with this it's kind of like feedback so if it's
if the rhythm in practice is i do a rep coach gives me feedback if it's like a one-to-one
ratio um the player is going to be completely relying on the coach in the game that's when
you start seeing players look back at the coach all the time right and uh the tv feedback is the
same way so if the feedback is or if the rhythm is i do a rep coach gives me feedback and i check
the monitor if it's all the time i mean you're gonna it's you're putting crutches on the athlete
so um so what we do is we just tell them hey just the tv
is there you can check it out if you want to and that kind of um and if i see them looking at it
every time i'll start kind of being like hey like did you need to like what did you feel make sure
you're feeling it more than thinking but for the most part they're pretty good like this these
players are older so they they know not to they don't need to look at it every single time but
um so uh anecdotally um like when i was coaching canada i think the first two three weeks like we
didn't have any video replay and i could feel how much longer it was taking to get some
concepts in place so so just this is just anecdotally for me i do feel like learning
speeds up with the uh video replay uh but just like coaching feedback it can't be a crutch and
it can't be some nervous tick or uh um i've even seen players kind of like study the video so you
can't give them feedback because they're embarrassed you know so like you gotta you
gotta watch all that and make sure uh you know the most important thing is that the athlete is
actually learning not that they're just listening to feedback or that they're studying the videos
like are they actually learning in a way that's going to help them in the game so
that's my big note on it so it's just it should just be an occasional it's a nice tool to have i
do think it accelerates learning but it can't be an all-the-time crutch the big question is here
of course it's not a big question at all uh just a figure of speech how many times have you
switched off the tvs when you're like okay stop watching now uh i usually eyeball it so if i see
um if so really like the two the two measures for me for a player are like was that rep better
or was that mistake a different mistake so if i if i see if i see two or three reps and they made
the exact same mistake then my my alarm starts going off like are we actually engaged in this
um and if i see three similar mistakes with checking the the replay then i start being like
like we're not just using flashy toys here like you know like it's like what what are you actually
trying to do right now you know and um you know sometimes i'll say more supportive than that
based on the engagement level but um as a coach that's really what i'm looking like was that
mistake different or was that rep better um and i'll i'll probably give two similar mistakes but
but this drill is so controlled if the athlete is doing the exact same thing three times in a row
like it's hard for me to believe that they're in it um so if they're looking at the
i'd be like what what are you looking at you did like you you know what you did there yeah so
uh that's it's i think that's just where teaching comes in you know so now we're working on row
one which um
yeah that was that's been a big focus for me is to just make sure we can side out a row one faster
you know it's always it's always a challenging rotation because your pin hitters are usually
playing opposite positions that they're they're normally hitting so you can get stuck there uh
pretty quick so i'm trying to make sure that we give like a fair amount to it each day and i think
i think because i'm talking so long excuse me uh this must be one of the first times we've done
this format this year because usually we snap out of it pretty quick um so i think i'm explaining
row one i'm explaining how the
opposites are going to switch uh and then once we break out exactly what i'm doing and then the
the group that was just hitting are now going to serve with uh aaron i'm just gonna go there at
the start which is just okay a bit i know yeah i'm talking for a long time here so this must be
uh one of the new first times we're doing it and then yeah i can tell the student managers
are trying to figure out what to be so there's a lot of first time stuff going on here um so we
have a row one situation here so we have our opposite so
we stack when this we run a six two so when this opposite is in her row one she's in a stack
so she's sliding in um but i'm also trying to get the outsides red so this is kind of like a
made up this isn't really an accurate rotation one i got the opposite hidden i got sorry i got
the outside passing hitting a red which would be like a spread row one and then i got the opposite
sliding in so they're both doing their own things here um and i have the same thing going on in the
other courts but uh the theme is the rotation one i'm trying to get everybody the reps to do that
they need in their row one and i try to tutor it a little better um i'm talking a lot to the outside
about trying to because they're right-handed on the right side trying to get them to approach
straight uh and then trying to get the setter to get the ball uh one ball further out for that red
and then uh trying to get this speed consistent we call it a so that two ball in the middle we
call it a blue um but i'm trying to get the i'm trying to get the setter in the middle to
run that at um so those are the kind of things we're working on here and i just got i got a guy
trying to re-block he's pretty medium at it but there's at least a little little interference there
for the hitters again you can see that we're keeping it random with the serves and the passes
are going all over the place so the setter's got to read which is really important i don't want the
setter just being like a robot you know so again so nice when you have a coach who has the arm that
she has you know you can see she just went from a spin to a flow and she's just just so nice for
the uh
passers to get those kind of random balls you know that's a that's the tempo i think they're
trying to go for right there like a little bit lower of a two higher than a one lower than a two
so they're working on that uh our outside went too far into past that so i'm probably
gonna say something to her uh that set was too tight so just all the stuff that they're working
on so again it's really nice to have a blocker there that's their feedback the set was too tight
and that wasn't the swing they want so yeah off they go a lot of really good learning here
yeah
about the switch let's see them i have to switch fuck a lot of balls and then we can move to
sure check out the next segment is uh this blue ball is the ball you just play with this with
this middle or is something that you try out with it with all of them um it's pretty common
play i would just call it a blue um for for our middle sets just the way i organize them like if
it's like your traditional quick sets i have them be numbers um if it's like the slide sets behind
the setter i have them be numbers um if it's like the slide sets behind the setter i have them be numbers
those letters like sml for short mid-long and then i have i have colors i had a uh when i was at
lmu i had a middle with an incredible arm and i was just trying to get to the ball more so we just
started setting two balls in different locations on the court so we so we use those as colors so i
had a white a blue and a gray so i just had to keep everything clear so number was uh if it was
a number it's like a traditional quick set if it's a color is a loop and if it was a letter it was a
slide set too tight so row one takes a lot of work
this was more or less also here uh 11 12 minutes and i'm gonna skip to the white board some white
board action yeah 12 minutes sounds right it's probably six minutes on each court um i try to
pick even numbers so everybody gets the equal amount of time yeah i'm curious what happens next
because i have like a volleyball hitter i guess yeah it's gonna it's the first two minutes it's
just um moves without a ball i guess drive all about moves warm up yeah first time out
so talk about ball setter ball hitter we're gonna introduce it with a serve um and a bounce from me
maybe something else and i'm talking about the situation we're gonna focus on from a block
defense standpoint um and then i give them once i talk about that then i give them 60 seconds to
just get on the court and either do defensive or blocking moves uh just to get ready just to get
ready to go um yeah i think too like blocking is one of those things like blocking is
blocking is a tough skill because it's so relatively well it's relatively
important compared to some of the others the other skills but it's so hard uh to do it well
and it can get so complicated so fast so so right now they're just they're just locking their
movements in for 60 seconds uh coaches are just giving them a little bit of feedback
um and then we're gonna get into it like i said in a minute less than a minute now
you see the barrels are sprawling um that's you know sprawling is such an important activity too
to dig the ball and it's like you got to get yourself comfortable enough to
where you feel like you can go really fast with it and you can cover a long distance so um
you can see like they're choosing their own moves but you can see they're sprawling just because we
tried to hammer it into them how important it is to be able to do it
uh middles are doing some x2 emergency moves right there that's a really important move
um if i had to guess right now i think the laveras are just trying to see how much ground
they can cover on their sprawls just as they do their little warm-up that that opposite just made
that block move she's gotten so much better so like she's she's really been focusing on her job
creating force off of it i just like how intentional they were you know um that was
really self-motivated that was cool to see and we're going to get into it so the focus is on
the near side the block defense side um i like standing on the offense side through the net just
so i can see the blockers eyes so i'm going to focus on the blockers uh ej aaron johnson she's
the the woman there dressed in black like she's going to focus more on the diggers
um aaron uh again aaron's more the serving coach he's going to focus just mainly on
the serve uh and then casey the girl that we talked about i've had the good arm i'm having
her stand more at the pole she's looking at our crates and converts so basically how we're digging
how high we're digging it what kind of set we get out of it then uh then we're playing so we're
just keeping score here i believe so we just did a serve let's see what the second ball is looks like
aaron's gonna spin it i'm already talking to him uh i talked a lot during ball set about hitters so
this is very much a this is like a midpoint so we've gone from tutors i'm doing a long string
so we've done tutors which is a really slow activity we're gonna get into competitive
sixes after this so this is really a nice intermediate step or like we're playing
sixes there's a score on it but the emphasis is still teaching like we're really trying to
get things in place on the block defense side and uh before we get into sixes and just start
running crazy um so you're gonna see a ton of feedback in this drill this is very much a
teaching drill uh sets an insistent ball so he said a red yeah so i think the focus might have
been set into red on the insistent
ball so we have a serve we have a bounce looks like i'm doing the bounce from area one so we're
working on long string out assist the balls where blockers have more time to see the set make sure
their crossover matches where the set's going um i think a huge mistake in blocking i think
blockers get on the hitter way too early when they know where it's going and then they uh they
get there too early and start reaching out to the hitter because their their moves not in sync with
the timing of the play um so we're just working on that i believe so and then we'll go back to it
so it'll be a serve uh it'll be a bounce from area one and then an insistent ball it looks like
that's a great serve oh here comes my bounce oh i'm shifting around so we must have covered all
those three spots i think i'm randomizing the bounce so the bounce is always going to be out
of system but this one's close closer to the hitter uh so in that case we want the middle
blocker to do a little get going like create a little rhythm into their move because we know
where the ball is probably going to go um so usually this time of year i've covered each
court in terms of out of system and how we want to play it and i'm randomizing the bounce now
and then it looks we're probably gonna do an insistent ball here again there's gonna be a
lot of feedback in this drill i'm talking to the opposite about the cross yeah because she uh
they just had a chance to uh defend a bump set so i just want her to get turned more in her
crossover get more out of it uh i'm for sure okay so i'm talking to that middle about the
rhythm creator so she she like shuffled and stopped and then made another move and i want
her to have just a little bit of rhythm and flow
into the full move um she's a freshman and just trying to pick it up and so now we're doing an
insistent ball and uh i'm not sure if i had a criteria on this insistent ball it might i might
have just been introducing in system offense um and just seeing what our eyes look like in all
three situations so we have a sir i think uh i think for this time of year so it was a serve
a bounce i could randomize the bounce and then uh just an insistent ball that i knew we would set
fast so i think i was um just introducing all three
segments and wanted to see what our eyes look like in those three situations so you have the
serve when you don't know what's going to happen you have a bounce when you kind of know where
it's going you have an insistent ball where it's going to be fast um and you guys want to see how
well we can look at the setter and uh read the play based on those three situations so a little
bit of this drill is a little bit of an evaluation for me for like where we're actually where our
eyes are actually at for each three phases of the game so i saw the set pretty well so there's
two experienced players makes sense and we're just gonna
rinse repeat uh throughout the drill pretty good read there so yeah that's pretty much the drill
that's the sequence of it so we call this drill six ball so it's uh so three balls going one way
three balls going this way so it's a serve and then some ball that of a situation we want to
create and then a serve that way and then same thing going this way whoever wins four out of six
wins one game and we play we play four we play four games total so you need to win three out of
six so i like it because obviously it's a lot of serving we we're in a rotation for that game
um it uh it allows us to work on the ball that we want to work on um and uh it's really competitive
it's like it's really really easy to understand like i need four out of six to win the game i need
three out of four games to win the round um so there's there's a really good rhythm uh to the
drill as well so so three three balls go that way and then three balls go this way unless the
um and again we're in the last part of practice now so our feedback will still obviously we're
still giving feedback but it should be going like way down now especially compared to the
drill that we had before um this is their time to compete and process and uh with this drill i'm
trying to put them in a situation that's creating the learning they need to learn anyway so that's
a bonus ball because we missed the serve so this this rally doesn't count uh now is the second ball
so we just did a serve we missed it so we did a bonus ball oh she's serving again
i might have missed it let's see what the next ball is i think so we're going uh we're going
serve spin serve that's what we're doing so we're trying to get it in we're trying we're obviously
working a little bit more on in system uh offense and defense today we had that uh spinning ball
center ball hitter to get an assistant ball and now we're we're adding a spin also so if i remember
right we're trying to get our speed going better on offense that's why we're doing a spin to create
in system situation have our setter focus on the speed to the pins
um so it's serve spin serve uh six balls both directions and you can see i'm not giving a ton
of feedback here i'm just i'm just making sure the rhythm of the drill is is rolling
so this is ball number six uh the other thing i like about this drill if there's a tie if it's
three three then we do a money ball so we pick someone to serve and they play that rally out
that gets a little more pressure on that serve which is really important to try to manufacture
for games so i love that part of it too if uh if at the end of the round if it's two games
two games well then we'll do a money ball for the whole game and then we'll do a money ball for the
whole round so again like anytime you can create little pressure opportunities for servers and
passers that's money because that's a that's such the problem with getting transferred into the game
is the is the fear people feel like in overcoming that and uh you know getting getting competitive
in those situations instead that is the the coach picking a player or just happens to be
the player that's like around closest to the car to serve a ball or uh we can do it however we want
but um you know aaron the serving coach
you know if i yell money ball like he generally knows who he wants to put to give that opportunity
to um so and again the the team knows what it means too so they kind of you know they start
getting on each other a little bit and uh again it's just really healthy competitive pressure in
those moments uh that's really the drill so it's just gonna run i gotta have a run for yeah six
eight ten balls uh the coaches are all coaching their areas so like this is when i really start
focusing on the offense when we get to sixes um i'm really just trying to stay locked in on the
offense and uh ej who's back is to us she's really focusing on block defense and then kc who's at the
pole um she's she's focusing on an area of the block defense that ej wants her to focus on so
ej can talk about the rest of the stuff um you know uh and then aaron benning uh is focused
coaching serving so we're all just in our areas now um
we're not we're not stopping the drills now for feedback like we were before
and uh we're letting them compete and hopefully uh hopefully there's a download going on for the
players so there's been like so much learning and so much like specific focus in each each rep that
um hopefully this is a chance for them to play and just kind of subconsciously start
downloading the stuff they've been working on without hyper focusing on it you know they've
got to get in a competitive uh mindset but i just stopped it so obviously we weren't playing very
hard yeah there's a mini huddle of like 60 60
60 70 seconds yeah if i'm doing that then there's there's just something repeatedly
happening that either that we're not picking up on and it's it's generally not a
well it's like 99.9 um an eye work or awareness piece it's not uh there's no uh technical coaching
going on at this point it's it's more how we're playing the game and how we're competing and
and uh how we're executing so yeah i think you can see why we're working on the in-system offense
going on so like we're trying to get the tempo you can see location suffering hitters need to
recognize what the set's giving them so just all the stuff you have to work on uh to get your offense
calibrated you still had it was still semi-comfortable at the first of september to
to have these issues so i think all that's fine what's that second it's still some like it was
still semi-comfortable to have those things going on at the first of september this season
exactly exactly every step further it's over
not so much yeah except for me like i i really it's kind of like what we're talking about with the
tvs and stuff i i really don't care about mistakes i expect them to happen i mean i'm constructing
the practice to get those mistakes happening what i care about is the engagement you know
just like is either like is it getting better or are new mistakes being made um but if i don't see
one of those two things that's when i start being like okay we're just not we're not engaging in
this i don't know if we're still competing here or not oh i think actually i think about i think
it's a little bit more of a one-on-one competition so we have uh like i said we have two different we
run a six two so we have one of our rotation ones is a stack and then the other one our
rotation four which is still kind of a one is a spread just having those two different lineups
uh compete each day against each other i believe it's i do it a bunch of different ways i think
this one is first team to 12 i think it's going serve toss that way first team to 12 wins and
serve toss that way first team to 12 wins so we're just getting our row one work in
so i think this is our final competitive activity
so if you notice the the activity we just did before we were not in row one we were in rotations
two and three so we were we were in the other rows that we play in and then this
um between the tutor and this you can see how much time we're putting into row one on this day
um yeah because what what we normally find is like halfway through the season you figure out
your rotation one is terrible and it's too late by then so just trying to make sure we give it
i don't know i'm not sure how this long swim went to go about 15 minutes probably
um yeah again 12 12 minutes yeah yeah so this goes we do this we've been doing this every day
we finished with a row one competition every day so we were just making sure that we hit it every
single day um so that's what this is i think there's there's still one i can see but i don't
see the end point so there's gonna be after these 12 minutes they're gonna be a while there's gonna
be a whiteboard moment and then
it's it's probably gonna be it's six six on six
out of a serve but i don't know if it's yeah i think it might just be flipping the
uh the other way it might be the other the other row one's turn to compete so like this
is all one way and then we then we flip it the other way check it out and i like these activities
because it's easier to coach when you keep someone on offense for a while you can just give them
feedback so much easier and they can
compete you're not you know there's there's a much better rhythm to it too you don't really
need to stop and um so we call these like one-way activities just because the offense is staying on
the offense i like it when we can do it this way you need both but these are these are really
these are easier to give feedback to oh so that was a trance toss so um so we did this how we if
you want to go back to that real quick um this is how we enter transition balls i don't know if
can you go back here i'm attempting to but this is not the the best i'm just gonna see if we can
have a middle setting that's fine because after this action okay yes it's gonna come now yeah so
so it should set up so coach aaron benny at the end line is going to toss the ball to the middle
front who is going to set to either pin just like that so she's going to set to either spin and then
the pin has to spin it over and then we're live after that so our hitters have to transition out
of that live
i love that because that's exactly what transition is like so i feel like most transition gets caught
like on a box or the coach is standing and spinning it over the block but that's not
what makes transition hard um the reason a lot of transition moves are bad is because the
the blocker slash transition hitter is two seconds behind the play like you know they they
made a bad read on the set they didn't find the ball now they're stuck so it's not that they
don't know how to transition it's like they're completely lost so i i love doing this because
that's the exact i sequence that happens in the rally
you read the block if you don't block it our key is if you don't block it track it so if you don't
block it your eyes should be up before you land and then that pivot is what helps you fly off the
net so i feel like the sequencing of it is exactly what happens in the game so um and then
it's just all these nice little ball touches you know our middle has to set a ball our outside has
to spin it with hand control um so there's all these nice little benefits to it so i i really
like it um that's that's how we introduce a transition ball there's the train stops again
so then they set behind so there's a little read going on we got a bad dig that's gonna happen so
there's you know i just i like how game like this is you know it's kind of like uh we're talking
about running the the middle hitter tutor off of a standing float like if you can't set your
middles off of the standing float you're not going to set your middles in the game um and it's
kind of the same thing like if we can't dig a spin we're not going to dig anything anyway so
like it it gives us a nice uh standard uh and feedback loop and kind of healthy pressure to
execute some plays yeah yeah like this was a
this is the thing that this is the the bar where we don't want to go under
yeah exactly exactly yeah so it looks like we're going serving a trance toss um this way
and yeah i was basing that off you know so it's really rotation one versus row four even though i
called the drill row one versus row one um so i i based the second ball off what i thought that
specific rotation needed so the the row one that was in a stack i gave them an insistent ball uh
because i think they were still working on the tempo
of the blue uh and then this the row four the second rotation when i gave them a trans ball
because we had uh the opposite and the outside had to stay on their off side so i want to get
them more comfortable in the transition yeah and there's the trans ball she couldn't hit that so
she had to set that over so again that's just the live read so as we're doing these trans tosses if
if you're on the side where you're going to be receiving the ball if she can't jump and spin it
over we expect you to get off like a free ball so it's just
i just love how it's completely specific to the game and eye work that you need uh to transition
well i've seen all sorts of crazy entries like to teaching transition i've seen coaches like
bullet under nets or just all this non-gay like and i know like i know it makes you like
feel good because kids are running around and sweating but it's just so if that's not the
challenge in transition you know it takes it takes a minute to teach someone how to run off
you know like the reason they don't do it is it's
it's almost always an eye work reason yeah the recording stops here okay or your recording stops
here and you still do something yeah recording might stop we uh yeah usually we finish with
like uh like one we do a lot we'll do four in a row where we'll have a we'll have i'll just have
two to three passers um either in the rotation that they want to work in or the scenes they want
to work in and i'll have everybody else lined up the server so like it has the rhythm of like
so it's not like it's not rapid fire serve you know it's like
serve you know so it's a little bit more slower like a game and everybody's focused on those
passers and we just don't leave until they get four in a row so i feel like that all eyes on
those passers and kind of like how slow it is uh it just creates it's like let's get out of this
let's get out of this what you want to feel so i like uh finishing with that and it's it's a nice
natural cool down like i i want the the volume to be really low at that point