so you can play this any way you want you can bonus any way you want and how you can really
spice it up at the end just another idea here for coaches let's say there is a tie 4-4 after
three serves each right score is 4-4 we always want to break a tie so that starts maybe with
one serve each way and uh you can have a who's going to be our xena warrior so we know where
this ball is going so okay our xena warrior is going to be amanda she's back on the court and
this ball is going to go to amanda and if she kills it game over because xena warrior she took
care of that's how we build our women up that's how we build confidence that's how we put pressure
on certain players um in a situation where you know two blockers are gonna be all over you you
know defense is ready for you everybody's ready for you everybody knows where the ball is going
but guess what you still gotta kill the ball
so we call it xena warrior is that right um and there's ways that you can really make this
extremely extremely competitive and while you're also learning here i don't determine who xena
warrior is i ask hey who's going to be xena warrior you're going to have same people raising
their hands same two i go i go i go and you will have some that will never raise their hand so that
tells you quite a bit is that right so then i'm like no no right now this guy or this girl is
going to be xena warrior
because you want to put them in a situation where it's like yeah you gotta you gotta take some
challenges here you gotta you gotta be every now and you're gonna be in a situation where
you're gonna be set you gotta feel comfortable dealing with this kind of adversity so that's
another wrinkle you can throw in this practice so it can it becomes very very very competitive