so two years ago i did like a big study on um a block and it basically i did a bunch of custom
codes on um you know if the block is open if there is one block if the middle blocker is reaching
into close if the middle blocker is straight over with a seam um if the middle blocker is reaching
like in and leaving a seam um if the outside the blocker is reaching out the outside blocker is
straight and if we are pressed with our hands over the net on the time of the contact and then
i did like a bunch of calculations from that or like a bunch of different like you know combinations
so single block all that kind of stuff by far the most important thing for us in that season was
that we were pressed so it didn't matter if the middle reached or they went straight or they left
a seam or or our outside even reached out like it didn't it just didn't matter as much as us being
pressed over the net um so of course you know
we're so ingrained in the things that we we think should be correct that like don't reach out on the
block they'll expose you and stuff like that that i i have to do study to check am i saying stuff
that even is real or am i saying it just because i know it from my past and from coaches that have
told me it before so um it really forced me to go okay like you know of course it did show that
being straight over as an outside was better than reaching out as an outside but only by
like a few percent um what was
more important was that we were pressed press press press press press so most of our feedback
gets on obviously we need to be lined up in the right position um and getting pressed in time
because if we're not pressed in time we're not going to get like we're not going to slow the
attacker down the measure that i use with opposition hitter efficiency i'm sure there
are better measures or different ways you can do that but i use opposition hitter efficiency
and the opposition hitter efficiency when we had a a press block was like really low