the two the two measures for me for a player are like was that rep better than the last one
or or was that mistake a different mistake so if i if i see if i see two or three reps and they
made the exact same mistake then my my alarm starts going off like are we actually engaged
in this um and if i see three similar mistakes with checking the the replay then i start being
like like like we're not just using flashy toys here like you know like it's like what what are
you actually trying to do right now you know and um you know sometimes i'll say more supportive
than that sometimes i'll be more direct than that based on the engagement level but um as a coach
that's really what i'm looking like was that mistake different or was that rep better um and
i'll i'll probably give two similar mistakes but but this drill is so controlled if the athlete
is doing the exact same thing three times in a row like it's hard for me to believe that they're in it