So we do, like, a lot of serve and passing reception.
Like, we just do a lot.
It's important.
Our serve for us is one of the biggest, like, points of our game
where I like to distinguish us from other teams.
And so we do a lot of this.
This is just called set a better.
So it's a three-big-point game.
Basically, the whole reception is working as a group
and the whole serve is working as a group.
So you've got to get three good receptions in a row to get a big point
or you've got to get three good serves in a row to get a big point.
However, I'm adding on top of this set a better.
So if it's a good pass, a good reception, and the setter gets it in,
then confirmed, you get your, like, reception point.
If they miss, then it becomes a serve point.
And if they get a ball in that is not a good pass,
then you upgrade it to a good point.
So it's just I don't do it too much because, honestly,
setting into targets is, like,
one thing that, again, is not always the measure,
but it's kind of fun.
It puts a little bit of pressure on the setter to see if they keep their
technique and they put work in that in situations.
And it's a great reception game, a three-big-point game,
because it's very competitive.
There's a lot of pressure in that.
And you've got to get three in a row to get a big point.
And once you get to three big points, you are the winner.
And that's it.
That's the game we play.
And we serve and we run to the other side.
And very often, sorry, yeah, we serve and then you run to the other side
and you get a good point.
We're serving from both sides.
And very often I say that they have to serve from one and one
and then from five and five so that, again, we're varying our position.
I've got to give that instruction or they forget because players can't
remember everything.