i think right now you should be seeing yeah i think it's four slides and maybe it's good to
explain like in general like what are the how is it separated if you want yeah if you want me to
zoom in i can zoom in also no no worries okay so on the top left we just have any notices that we
need to remind the girls of and we put them on there otherwise we kind of forget things day to
day um after that we have a countdown to something if we have anything important coming up we keep a
little countdown just to keep them yeah excited and to see what truly is the you know actual goal
that's coming up and then depending on kind of the the way for the situation we have some focuses like
here we have like a spotlight things that we're focusing on and this was a defense readiness um
i would say one of the weaknesses of this team is is is our like defensive
i don't want to say ability because i believe that can be changed but we are a power team
for sure we're strong servers we're great attackers um and we need to keep improving on our on our
defense side of things and so that was has been and still is quite a big focus for us so just
you know being disciplined on our position keeping our services up so that we're able to touch the
ball and being aggressive in in us um yeah going for balls really and then i believe that's the
second touch there um i can swim in with just yeah no worries second touch is so important for us um
that everybody knows that they can set that they can step in that they can get the ball on the net
that we don't have any hesitation um and that we get the ball in and on and that is still a really
big thing for us this was back in october we're like december now and this is still a huge thing
for us so i don't think that that changes so that's something that we want to improve on um and
we still see in our game that it's you know really important because there's just like 50 of the time
you're in situations that are a little bit less than ideal and we need to really be getting that
ball on the net um so then we need to really be getting that ball on the net um so then we need to
have our aggressive attacking like which really means like finding a way to score like i think
that in women's volleyball especially they revert the plan b too quickly and i would like to really
get rid of that plan b as much as possible um so can you score like question mark or like if you
think you can't you probably can um and let's just like reach out about how you can do that
and then having you know a better range of vertical range um so hitting high hands like
down and then now a horizontal range as well um tips wipes everything like just if you're going to
exploring our vertical and horizontal range is is really really important for us and that was a big
focus during this particular week that we have these practices sniper serving want to be really
great servers so um and we take a lot of risk i'm sure we have the highest error we do have the
highest percentage in the league right now um but we are pretty effective with what we're doing so
we want to be able to serve from both sides we want to be able to serve short long it doesn't
mean just whacking the ball every time but just that we are really going for a point or an overpass
um and just being relentless on that aggression so it's just doesn't matter if we're having a bad
day and we've got you know nine service areas in the first set doesn't mean we need to slow it down
we need to just keep going with it because eventually it does work for us and when it does
we win and then some coach focuses so the coaches kind of know what they're looking at um this part
of the board changes like right now if i look at the whiteboard i have some i have some spotlight
and then i have some key statistics that just to show why we've been working on some stuff in
particular up there right now is a step in touch
um i did a study on like the quality of our second start touch and the the attackers like
percentages of it basically um just to show a little bit like how many good sets we're getting
how many bad sets we're getting why we're focusing on it so much what happens when we get a good set
out of system um and things like that and so i had that key stats up there but it kind of depends
what we have on that side of the board depending on um yeah what what really is important in that
moment so um yes then it's the practice the warm-up here i for some reason don't
have what is the warm-up but sometimes i take it sometimes it's an individual one with the girls
usually it's like uh we give a certain amount of time like a structured um autonomy so we give like
three minutes for them to do band work three minutes core a few minutes dynamic or something
like this depending on a little bit the situation um always i almost always have a little mini game
just to get things fired up a little bit to have a bit of competitiveness in the in the practice and
i'd start on a on a good note um and then yeah pretty much the exercises as many cases i can put
or things to put on that day i'm a little bit worse some days and other days and we always are
so um and then usually the six on six portion on the on the right side there i'll switch to like
in the afternoon practice you have the more detailed warming up i think actually that that
that's a morning these ones are morning practice with a different writing that's a morning practice
that the one you had was an afternoon practice yeah so i messed up with the name no it's okay
yeah yeah yeah um so
yeah interesting that you talked about uh yeah i don't know if like if you use this for a video or
not i started like watching female volleyball higher level female volleyball let's say um top
eight maybe right now even like top 20 teams in europe so that's like already a pretty broad band
of quality whatever um but for sure they're like there's an important fall off between the top 12
and maybe 12 to 20 the thing that you just said about being consistent in your aggressivity
not like going for the easy option and trying to count on your own transition game which is
always dangerous and like depending on yeah it's really interesting like a lot of coaches focus on
you know defense and trans and of course here i have a spotlight on our defense because we're not
we're not amazing at it but um we win the games by being like by scoring the points like we win
by scoring points so that's that's the end of it that's the end of it you know so we need to be
scoring the points and i don't know i think it's
it's kind of easy to coach women's volleyball because you just got to look at the men's
and and and translate it across it's honestly it's five years we're five years behind in in
women's volleyball i think um all the time and so if we look across at the men how they're playing
i think they give us a lot of clues into what we really can do and and how to push the women into
kind of edges of their abilities a little bit more so yep aggression control and that's why
i think that's why we win a lot
yeah i know for sure maybe the female game is way more influenced by the american school or
american volleyball there is more culture of not making a mistake and keep on playing going for
the rally uh yeah and and then and then in men's volleyball there is no american school yes but i
don't know that it's american i think in general females have been like overcoached and they've
been you know but it's like a little bit of our problem and the problem of the coaches like we
ask a lot of questions we want to know everything before we get started we need like pure
instructions like if i say just go try it that's not going to go down very well i need to give
shows how to how to how to do everything step by step and when that mentality changes and you just
try stuff then you kind of create and you grow so i do think that females in general need to be
pushed to just like think a little bit less and just try a little bit more because they're super
athletic then it's lower than the men so we have the same advantage you know and we should be able
to do the same stuff but um i listened to i was watching you know some champions league games the
we if we get a highball situation we just need to put it in to get ourselves a good situation and
then to be able to play block defense and you know that team absolutely got crushed and it's just
like i don't want to say what's right or wrong i know we all have to coach in our own philosophies
and this for sure fits me a lot better and my personality in the way that i coach and the way
that my teams function to be aggressive but like i don't want to i want to be playing against teams
that are playing it safe because i believe that it's in our hands to win the game right so like
okay we have to get it right we have to play the tough shots we have to score these right points
we'll probably win the game it's harder like of course we can lose it because if they're safe and
we and we error our way out to that bloody shithole then we're going we're going to lose you know but
generally it's in our hands no yeah it's about making points for sure so you can also start to
recruit players that maybe other people don't recruit because like they have a deficiency in
receiving and you're like also it has to receive and then you have three receiving players that are
all one meter 78 and nobody's piping in
um yeah yeah yeah i i definitely build teams more towards when i can choose because this honestly i
don't have a huge amount of choice all the time like but when i can choose i build teams to work
towards aggression